Guide to the Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī Family Papers AD.MC.065
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Photographs, 1904-1993, and undated
  - Oversized prints
    - Group portrait, unidentified, featuring A.Z. Abu Shadi, circa 1925 (Box OS-5, Folder 10)
    - Group portrait, unidentified, featuring A.Z. Abu Shadi, circa 1920s (Box OS-5, Folder 11)
    - Group portrait, unidentified, perhaps in Port Said, featuring A.Z. Abu Shadi, circa 1920s (Box OS-5, Folder 12)
    - Group portrait, Bee Kingdom League members, Alexandria, with A.Z. Abu Shadi seated third from left, in meeting with agricultural ministers, circa 1930s (Box OS-5, Folder 13)
    - Group portrait, of schoolgirls, with Safeya Abu Shadi, seated second row, far left, circa 1930s (Box OS-5, Folder 14)
    - Amina Naguib. One framed image, depicting her at age 30 (photomechanical reproduction of a pencil sketch, in cameo frame), undated
    - Bamford, Annie. Framed photograph, in oval mount, 1902
    - Bamford, Annie. Framed photograph, in oval mount, 1914
- Printed material, 1898-2010
  - Publications by Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, 1927-1958
    - al-Ālihah: ūpirā ramzīyah dhāt thalāthat fuṣūl = "The Goddesses: Symbolic opera in three acts," (Cairo: Dār al-ʻUṣūr lil-Ṭabʻ wa-al-Nashr), 1927 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Akhnātūn Firʻawn Miṣr: ūbirā dhāt thalāthat fuṣūl = "Akhenaton: Historic opera in three acts," (Egypt: Dār al-ʻUṣūr lil-Ṭabʻ wa-al-Nashr), 1927 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Mukhtārāt waḥy al-ʻām [part 1, 16 pages] (Cairo: Dār al-ʻUṣūr lil-Ṭabʻ wa-al-Nashr), 1928 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Rubāʻīyāt ʻUmar al-Khayyām = The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, rendered into Arabic verse by A.Z. Abushady (Cairo: Rābiṭat al-Adab al-Jadīd), 1931 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Muṣṭafá al-zaʻīm [poem addressed to Muṣṭafá al-Naḥḥās Pasha](al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1932 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Madhhabī = Since my love (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1351 a.h. (1932) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - al-Yawm al-rahīb: Rithāʼ Fuʼād al-Awwal (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1936 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - ʻAqīdat al-ulūhah (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1936 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Risālat Muḥammad: li-munāsabat al-Mawlid al-Nabawī al-karīm, (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1937 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - al-Māl fī al-Islām = Money in Islam (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1937 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Aẓamat al-Islām = Greatness of Islam (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), undated, circa 1937-1940 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Tawlīyat al-Fārūq (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1937 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Li-mādhā anā mu'min? = Why am I a believer? (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1937 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi: At random: thoughts on humanism (London: C.W. Daniel), 1937 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi: Egypt's Dilemma (speech delivered in Alexandria, March 1938), Cooperation Press (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - ʻAwdat al-rāʻī, majmūʻah shiʻrīyah = Return of the shepherd: Collected poems of A.Z. Abushady (Alexandria: Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun), 1942 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Min al-samāʼ = From the Heavens: Collected Poetry, 1949 (New York: Matba'at Jarīdat al-Yawmīyah) (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Min nāfidhat al-tārīkh ([Cairo]: al-Muqtaṭaf), November 1952 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Songs of Nothingness (mimeograph text, New York: Orientalia), 1953 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Tales of the Unbelievable," Orient Digest, August 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - al-Islām al-ḥayy [edited and compiled by Raḍwān Ibrāhīm] (al-Qāhirah: Rābiṭat al-Adab al-Ḥadīth), 1955 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shuʻarāʼ al-ʻArab al-muʻāṣirūn, Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi (edited with an introduction by Raḍwān Ibrāhīm), ([Cairo]: Dār al-Ṭibāʻah al-Ḥadīthah|), 1958 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Publications about Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, 1934-2004
    - Wakīl, Mukhtār. Rūwād al-shiʻr al-ḥadīth fī Miṣr (Al-Qāhirah: Maṭbaʻatah al-ṭalabah), 1934 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Edham, I.A.: Abushady the poet: a critical study (Leipzig: Gustav Fischer), 1936 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Harker, Leonard. Blazing the Trail: Reminiscences of A.Z. Abushady (London: C.W. Daniel), 1938 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Ibrāhīm, Muḥammad ʻAbd al-Fattāḥ. Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī: jawlah maʻa al-shāʻir al-nāthir ustādh al-jīl alladhī akhrajatahu Madrasat Abbūlū fī kitābātihi al-adabīyah (al-Qāhirah: Maktabāt al-Shaʻb), May 1955 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - ʻUzayzī, Rūkus ibn Zāʼid. Shāʻir al-insānīyah: Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Khafājī, Muḥammad ʻAbd al-Munʻim. Rāʼid al-shiʻr al-ḥadīth: Aḥmad Zakī abū Shādī (Cairo: [publisher not identified], 2nd edition, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Dirāsāt Islāmīyah [place of publication and publisher not identified], 40 pages, circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Dirāsāt adabīyah [place of publication and publisher not identified], 60 pages, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Abū Shādī fī al-mahjar: majmūʻah min maqālātihi wa-aḥādīthih ([al-Qāhirah]: Maktabat Miṣr), undated, circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī. Qaḍāyā al-shiʻr al-muʻāṣir (al-Qāhirah: al-Sharikah al-ʻArabīyah lil-Ṭibāʻah wa-al-Nashr), 1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Khafājī, Muḥammad ʻAbd al-Munʻim. Qiṣṣat al-adab al-mahjarī (Bayrūt: Dār al-Kitāb al-Lubnānī), 1973 (Volume 1)
    - Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī. al-Insān al-jadīd, wa-qaṣāʼid ukhrá: al-majmūʻah al-kāmilah li-shiʻrihi al-mahjarī ([Cairo]; al-Iskandarīyah: Dār wa-Maṭābiʻ al-Mustaqbal; Bayrūt: Muʼassasat al-Maʻārif), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Jawdat, Ṣāliḥ. Balābil min al-Sharq (Miṣr: Dār al-Maʻārif, as published in Iqraʼ (Cairo, Egypt)), August 1984 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi. al-Nayrūz al-ḥurr, wa-qaṣāʼid ukhrá ([Cairo]: Dār wa-Maṭābiʻ al-Mustaqbal ), 1988 (Volume 2)
    - Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī; Rūks ibn Zāʼid ʻAzīzī. Yawmīyāt al-Duktūr Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī, 1942 (ʻAmmān, al-Mamlakah al-Urdunīyah al-Hāshimīyh: Wizārat al-Thaqāfah), 1995 (Volume 3)
    - Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī: makhtārāt min diwān, al-Nayrūz al-ḥurr., 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Filasṭīn, Wadīʻ. Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī: al-āthār al-shiʻrīyah al-majhūlah (Bayrūt: Dār al-Jadīd), 2000 (Volume 4)
    - Karrū, Abū al-Qāsim Muḥammad. Ḥiwār wa-shuʻarāʼ (Tūnis: Dār al-Maghrib al-ʻArabī), 2001 (Volume 5)
    - Karrū, Abū al-Qāsim Muḥammad. Tarājim qaṣīrah: ṣuwar - iḍāfāt (Tūnis: Sharikah al-Tūnisīyah lil-Nashr wa-tanmīyat Funūn al-Rasm), 2004 (Volume 6)
  - Publications edited or published by Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, 1921-1939
    - The Bee World, edited by A.Z. Abushady, vol. 3 [bound volume, with numbers 1-12], June 1921 - May 1922 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - The Bee Kingdom, vol. 1, no. 6, June 1930 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - The Bee Kingdom, vol. 2, no. 12, December 1931 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Apollo: a monthly review, February 1934 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Apollo: a monthly review, December 1934 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 1, part 1, reprint of Vol. 1, Issues 1 to 6 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [September 1932 - February 1933] (Volume 7)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 1, part 2, reprint of Vol. 1, Issues 7 to 11 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [March - July 1933] (Volume 8)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 2, part 1, reprint of Vol. 2, Issues 1 to 6 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [September 1933 - February 1934] (Volume 9)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 2, part 2, reprint of Vol. 2, Issues 7 to 10 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [March - June 1934] (Volume 10)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 3, part 1, reprint of Vol. 3, Issues 1 to 3 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [September - November 1934] (Volume 11)
    - Apūllū. Bound volume 3, part 2, reprint of Vol. 3, Issue 4 (Bayrūt: Dār Ṣādir), [December 1934] (Volume 12)
    - Adham, E.I. Limādhā anā mulḥid? [Why am I an atheist?] (al-Iskandarīyah: Maṭbaʻah al-Taʻāwun), 1937 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - ʿAzzām, Ḥasan ʿAbd al-Laṭīf. Qāmūs al-tilmīḏ (Al-Iskandarīya: Maṭbaʿat al-Taʿāwun), 1937 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Maṭbaʻat al-Taʻāwun: various brochures and publications (Min Miṣr al-Farʻūnīyah, Mudhakarah....Ali Maher Basha, issue of "Al Imam" magazine), 1936-1939 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Publications with biographical association to Abu Shadi, 1898-2010
    - Hamdhānī, ʻAbd al-Raḥmān. Kitāb al-Alfāẓ al-kitābīyah (Beirut), 1898 (Volume 13)
    - German Simplified. Hugo's Simplified System (London: Hugo's Institute), undated, circa 1908 (Volume 14)
    - Lamplough, A.O. Egypt, and how to see it (London: Ballantyne and Co.), 1908 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Iddah, Jibrā'īl. Al-Qawā'id al-jalīyah fī 'ilm al-Arabīyah (Bayrūt Maṭba'at al-Ābā' al-mursalīn al-Yasū'iyyin), 1909 (Volume 15)
    - Lublin, Isabel. Primer of German Literature, 5th edition (London: Allen and Unwin), 1909 (Volume 16)
    - Tirard, H.M. The Book of the Dead (London: Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge), 1910 (Volume 17)
    - Murtaḍī, Muhammad. Badā'i al-qalam, undated, circa 1920s (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Zikrī, Anṭūn. al-Adab wa-al-dīn ʻinda qudamāʼ al-Miṣrīyīn (Miṣr: Maṭbaʻat al-Maʻārif bi-shāriʻ al-Fajjālah bi-Miṣr), 1923 (Volume 18)
    - Petrie, Flinders. Egyptian Tales from the Papyri, third edition (London: Methuen), 1924 (Volume 19)
    - al-Qamus al-lughat al-'arabiyah (1925) (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Salim, Muḥammad Aḥmad. Al-mufakirat al-naḥwīyah... (Egypt: Matba'at al-Amliyah al-Kibra), 1929 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - ʻAjjātī, ʻAbd al-Ḥamī̄d; Malṭī, Riyāḍ Jundī. Tārīkh al-funūn al-jamīlah fī al-Qurūn al-Wusṭá (al-Qāhirah: Dār al-Kitāb al-Miṣrī), 1929 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Pellett, Frank C. American Honey Plants, 3rd edition (Hamilton, IL: American Bee Journal), 1930 (Volume 20)
    - Belot, P. J.-B. Petit dictionnaire Francais-Arabe (Beirut: Imprimerie Catholique), 1930 (Volume 21)
    - Muḥammad Abū Shādī: dirāsah adabīyah tārīkhīyah, by ʻAbd al-Ḥamīd Kīlānī; ʻAbd al-Ḥafīẓ Rūbī (al-Qāhirah: Maṭbaʻat Ḥijāzī bi-jiwār qism al-Jamālīyah bi-al-Qāhirah), 1933 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Allen, M. Yate. European Bee Plants and Their Pollen, 1st edition (Alexandria: Bee Kingdom League), 1937 (Volume 23-24)
    - Mūsā, Nabawīya. Al- Marāʼa wa'l-ʻamal (unidentified publisher), 1939 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Bustānī, Fuʼād Afrām. Munjid al-ṭullāb: muʻjam madrasī ʻan munjid al-Ab Maʻlūf, 1941 (Volume 25)
    - Faroughy, A. A Concise Persian Grammar (New York: Orientalia), 1944 (Volume 26)
    - Ricordo di Genova. 32 vedute [place of publication and publisher not identified], undated, circa 1940s (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Lewis, Bernard. A handbook of diplomatic and political Arabic. ([London] Luzac), 1947 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Ṣayrafī, Ḥasan Kāmil. al-Shurūq (Egypt: Dar al-Ma'arif) [presentation copy to Hoda Abu Shadi Garnett in 1983], 1948 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Grout, Roy A., editor. The Hive and the Honey Bee, revised edition (Hamilton, IL: Dadant and Sons), 1949 (Volume 27)
    - Boyle, John A. A Practical Dictionary of the Persian Language (London: Luzac), 1949 (Volume 28)
    - Siddiqui, Mohammad Abdul Aleem. The history of the codification of Islamic law ... (Port-of-Spain, Trinidad: Anjuman sunnat-wal-jama'at), 1950 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Matḥaf al-Qibṭī (Cairo, Egypt). Le Musée Copte. ([Le Caire]: [S.O.P. Press]), 1950 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - al-Kitāb al-muqadis ay kutub al-ʻahd al-qadīm wa-al-ʻahd al-jadīd: wa-qad turajim min al-lughāt al-aṣlīyah (Beirut: Jamaʻīat al-Kitāb al-muqadis), 1951 (Volume 29)
    - Nāʻūrī, ʻĪsá. [typescript text, bound and stapled, of Arabic poetry, 55 pages, with accompanying letter, Amman, Jordan], 1952 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Abū Shādī, Ṣafīyah Aḥmad Zakī. al-Ughnīyah al-khālidah (al-Qāhirah: Rābiṭat al-Adab al-Ḥadīth), 1954 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Amīn, Aḥmad; Murrow, Edward R. ʻAllamatnī al-hayāh [This I Believe] (al-Qāhirah: Dār al-Hilāl), 1953 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - El-Gawhary, Mahmoud. Ex-Royal Palaces in Egypt: from Mohamed Aly to Farouk (Cairo: Dar al-Maaref), 1954 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - [VOA Arabic Service. Annual Report]. Ṣawt Amrīkā iḍāʼah ʻArabīyah, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Majallat al-Hajj (Makkah al-Mukaramah), Year 8, Issue 12, February 1955 (1374 A.H.) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - ʻAṭīyah, Jurjī Shāhīn. Sullam al-lisān fī al-ṣarf wa-al-naḥw wa-al-bayān: al-darajah al-rābiʻah, undated, circa 1950s (Volume 30)
    - Ṣawt al-ʻurūbah: La voix du Monde Arabe ([al-Qāhirah] [publisher not identified]), September 1955 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Adham Wanly: exposition retrospective (Alexandria: Musee des Beaux Arts, 1961) (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Seif Wanly: exposition retrospective des ses oeuvres de 1951 a 1961 (Alexandria: Musee des Beaux Arts) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Ramzī, Munīr. Barīq al-ramād (al-Qāhirah: Dār Sharqiyāt lil-Nashr wa-al-Tawzīʻ), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Edward R. Murrow's This I believe: selections from the 1950s radio series (Louisville, KY: This I Believe Inc.,), 2010 (Volume 31)
- Artwork, ephemera, realia, and sound recordings, 1876-1992
  - Art work, 1918-1955
    - Hassan, Muhammed. Untitled, oil painting portrait of Ahmed Zaki Abushâdy. Ca. 10.5 x 14.5 in. signed and signed dated at the margin, 1918
    - Hassan, Muhammed. Untitled, oil painting portrait of Annie Bamford. Ca. 10.5 x 14.5 in. signed and signed dated at the margin, 1918
    - Shabaan Zaky: pencil portrait of Safeya, studying at home in Alexandria, 1939 (Box OS-4, Object 22)
    - Fridon, ink portrait of Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, depicted as a microscope, undated (Box OS-4, Object 23)
    - Adham Wanly, "Return of the Shepherd," art work for cover of poetic anthology by A.Z. Abu Shabi, 1941 (Box OS-4, Object 24-a.)
    - Adham Wanly: "Return of the Shepherd," art work for cover of poetic anthology by A.Z. Abu Shadi, 1941 (Box OS-4, Object 24-b.)
    - Adham Wanly: portrait of A.Z. Abu Shadi, ink and water color, 1936 (Box OS-4, Object 25)
    - Paul Beer: charcoal sketch of A.Z. Abu Shadi, looking into a microscope, 1929 (Box OS-4, Object 26)
    - Seif Wanly: five sketches, on three leaves of paper, possibly for book cover art work, undated (Box OS-4, Object 27)
    - Adham Wanly, four small paintings, on folded card stock, 1950-1955 (Box OS-4, Object 28)
    - Seif Wanly: portrait of three women in field, in cubist manner, gouache on board, 1950 (Box OS-4, Object 29)
    - Seif Wanly: portrait of Clea Badaro, undated (Box OS-4, Object 30)
    - Adham Wanly: shepherdess, gouache on board, with inscription on verso dedicated to Safeya Abu Shadi, 1955, 1959 (Box OS-4, Object 31)
    - Seif Wanly: untitled, three women in rice field, oil on masonite, 1955 (Box OS-4, Object 32)
    - Sayed Ibrahim: illustrations for magazines edited by A.Z. Abu Shadi, including "Apollo" and "Bee Kingdom", undated, circa 1930s (Box OS-4, Object 33)
  - Ephemera, 1876-1992
    - Autograph book: Safeya Abu Shadi, with inscriptions, caricatures, and artwork, including two original illustrations from Adham Wanly, 1943-1946 (Box OS-3, Object 21a)
    - Autograph book: Hoda Abu Shadi, with inscriptions and artwork, including two original illustrations from Adham Wanly., 1943-1946 (Box OS-3, Object 21b)
    - Autograph book: Hoda Abu Shadi, with inscriptions and artwork, with one illustration from [Adham?] Wanly., 1946-1953 (Box OS-3, Object 21c)
    - Booklet: "Helwa" [Arabic cookbook with dessert recipes, stapled, leaves not cut, ca. 16 pages. Alexandria, Egypt.], undated (Box OS-2, Object 14)
    - Broadside: text by Muhammad Abu Shadi, "Kalamah ṣidq wa ākhlāṣ" [Word of sincerity and truth] (no place of publication), undated (Box OS-5, Folder 17)
    - Broadside: texts relating to Abu Shadi, unidentified, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Broadside: open letter from Nabawiyya Musa to Mustafa al-Nahas Pasha, regarding closure of schools, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Business cards, in leatherette wallet: primarily Arabic, including "Safeya Ahmed Zaki (Abu Shadi)," with and without notation "Washington," and various other cards, including "Hosni Nagib, Cairo" (Box OS-1, Object 6)
    - Commonplace book: given to Annie Bamford by Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, 1914-1917 (Box OS-6, Object 2)
    - Letterhead: Bee Kingdom League, 60 rue Menasce, Alexandria, Egypt, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Maps: Tunisia, Arabian Gulf (Kuwaiti government publications), undated, circa 1960s (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Mementos: Mohammed Mounir Ramzy (1): box ("Nofret Bath Soap") containing containing photos, seashells, trinkets, originally exchanged between M. Mounir Ramzy and Safeya Abushady, and kept after the former's death, 1945 (Box OS-1, Object 4)
    - Mementos: Mohammed Mounir Ramzy (2): Diary book, titled "My Confession Book," with poems by Safeya memorializing M. Mounir Ramzy, and pictures of him, 1945 (Box OS-1, Object 5)
    - Newspaper (tearsheet, original): Al Ahram, 5 August 1876 (Box OS-5, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper (photocopy): Al Ahram, 5 August 1876 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Postcards: album (titled "Post Card Album"), from Safeya Abushady, with images from Mexico (Mexico City and surroundings, Acapulco), undated, circa mid-1950s (Box OS-7, Object 37)
    - Postcards: bound collection of postcards (22) of pilgrimage sites in Makkah, A.H. 1372, circa 1953 C.E. (Box OS-2, Object 13)
    - Postcards: scenes in Egypt, unused, Lehnert and Landrock, Cairo, Undated, circa 1920s-1930s (Box OS-1, Object 7)
    - Postage stamps: Egyptian stamps honoring Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, and others (Talaat Harb). Single stamp, plate block, first day covers, and affixed to envelopes, 23 December 1992 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Program from Cinema Rio, Alexandria, Egypt, for showing of Walt Disney's film "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs," plus ticket for matinee screening of the same, November 1938 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Scrapbook: from Safeya Abu Shadi, news clippings, invitations, and photographs, chiefly about Prince Faisal, during his visits to the United Nations, including printed portrait of Faisal with his signature, 1947-1948 (Box OS-3, Object 19-a)
    - Scrapbook: from Safeya Abu Shadi, news clippings about Prince Faisal of Saudi Arabia, chiefly related to his visits to the United States, 1947-1958 (Box OS-3, Object 19-b)
    - Scrapbook: from Safeya Abu Shadi, news clippings, photographs and documents related chiefly to visit of Saudi Prince Abdullah bin 'Abd al Aziz to the United States, 1952 (Box OS-3, Object 19-c)
    - Scrapbook: gift to Safeya Abu Shadi, from her mother, containing postcards, greeting cards, and magazine cuttings, 1942, and undated (Box OS-6, Object 1)
  - Realia, 1917-1946, and undated
    - Album of pressed flowers and plants: prepared by Hoda Abu Shadi, as birthday gift for Safeya, containing specimens from garden of family's residence in Alexandria, 1945 (Box OS-8, Object 38)
    - Hat: tarbouche belonging to Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi (Object 40)
    - Lapel pins: Bee Kingdom League, undated, circa 1930s (Box OS-3, Object 20)
    - Name plate: Brass door plate embossed "Dr. A.Z. Abushâdy," used at home and office in Ealing, England 6.75 x 11 in., undated, circa 1917 (Box OS-6, Object 39)
    - Plaque: presented to Safeya Abushady upon her retirement from U.S. Government service, January 1985 (Object 43)
    - Suitcase: leather, monogrammed with initials of Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, used during journey from Alexandria to New York (1946) (Object 41)
    - Textile: Pollard, Sarah. Funerary needlepoint. N.d., commemorating the death of John Bradbury, et al. of Stalybridge, England, forebearers of Annie Abushâdy (née Bamford.) Ca. 29 in. x 25 in. (Box OS-6, Object 3)
    - Typewriter, Arabic, used by Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi: a pre-WWII model, manufactured by Continental and sold in Cairo by Wiesenthal. (Object 42)
  - Sound recordings, 1952-1970
    - Voice of America; United States Information Agency: Azan, the call to prayer on the minaret (transcription disk, 33 r.p.m.), undated, circa 1950s (Box OS-6)
    - Voice of America [?]: "The Poet Doctor," a dramatic work by Oliver Wendell Holmes, performed by Dr. A.Z. Abushady, Isa K. Sabbagh, Said Jibrin, and others, narrated by Boulos A. Malik, undated, circa early 1950s (Box OS-1, Object 10-a.)
    - Voice of America [?]: "Nefertiti and the Sculpture," by Dr. A.Z. Abushady (one open-reel tape, one CD-R disk, running time: 19:59), July 14, 1952 (Box OS-1)
    - [A remembrance of the poetry, art, and literature of Dr. Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, on the first anniversary of his death]: Recording, in Arabic, on cardboard disk, with portrait of Abu Shadi and accompanying text on recto, and photographs of American scenes on verso. Recording by Isa Khalid Sabbagh., undated, circa 1956 (Box OS-1, Object 11)
    - Nasser, Gamal Abdel. "I Can Hear it Now" featuring an interview with Gamal Abdel Nasser, by Howard K. Smith, edited by Edward R. Murrow and Fred W. Friendly, issued by Columbia Records (Vinyl record, 33 r.p.m., ML 5110), 1956 (Box OS-6)
    - Audiocassette: Salute to Radio Libya, featuring Safeya Abu Shadi, and others, 1968 (Box OS-2, Object 18)
    - Open reel tapes (2), 7.5 i.p.s., Arabic programming, 1970 and undated (Box OS-1, Object 10-b.)